

Curriculum Vitae for Eivind Storm Aarnæs

Personal information

Address: Maridalsveien 240 E-mail: eivind@xal.no

0467 Oslo Phone: $+47\ 988\ 84\ 317$

Born: 21.02.1991 Nationality: Norwegian

Summary

I have a masters degree in Computational Science from the University of Oslo, completed in 2016. My project was about a particle system modeling linear elasticity, and accelerating linear algebra computations using GPUs. From my studies leading to this degree I have gained broad knowledge about algorithms, numerical mathematics, and programming in several languages.

Prior work experience includes teaching programming: mostly one-to-one teaching in a lab setting, but also as lecturing and live coding in plenary settings. I have also worked with testing—both manual and automated, and with Android development and some minor Javascript development.

Technical skills

Frameworks OpenCL, Android, Node.js

Languages C/C++, Python, Javascript, Java, TeX/LaTeX Tools Git, CMake, Vim editor, Atom editor, IntelliJ IDEA

Education

2011 – 2014 Bachelor Degree in Applied Mathematics at the University of Oslo.

2014 – 2016 Masters Degree in Computational Science at the University of Oslo.

My thesis was titled "Sparse Matrix Storage Schemes for a Linear

System arising from a Discrete Model of Elasticity".

Professional experience

2017 –	IT Consultant at Expert Analytics AS.
2012 – 2015	Teaching Assistant at the University of Oslo in the course "INF1100:
	Introduction the programming with scientific applications". Only the autumn semesters.
	Was responsible for a weekly programming lab. I also corrected assignments for my class.
0012 0014	3
2013 – 2014	Summer intern and contract software developer at Teleplan Globe AS. Prototyped an Android app for logging mobile network parameters,
	and identifying all the cell towers the device communicated with.
2014 - 2014	Teaching Assistant at the University of Oslo in the course "INF1010:
	Object oriented programming". Only the spring semester.
	Shared responsibility for both reviewing the past weeks exercises in
	plenary for the entire course, and lecturing the pre-course for students
	with no prior knowledge in Java.
2013 - 2013	Teaching Assistant at the University of Oslo in the course "INF1010:
	Object oriented programming". Only the spring semester.
	Was responsible for a weekly programming lab. I also corrected as-
	signments for my class.
2012 - 2013	Summer intern at Teleplan Globe AS.
	Worked on testing web applications: both manually and by automating manual procedures.
	manual procedures.

Languages

English Professional working proficiency

Norwegian Native proficiency

Personal skills

OpenCL As part of my masters degree I have implemented OpenCL GPU ope-

rations for several sparse matrix schemes.

Reading Code Through my work as a teaching assistant I have read and graded

somewhere around 140 000 lines of code (Python/Java).

Extended descriptions of selected projects

Activity The norwegian land register (NO: "Matrikkelen")

Period April. 2017 — Role Developer

Staffing More than 10 developers

Volume 100%

Description I redesigned and implemented the algorithms for computing land bor-

ders using a specialized depth-first graph search.

expertanalytics.no

Tools Java, Oracle SQL, Hibernate, IntelliJ IDEA, JIRA, Confluence and

Perforce

Activity Region and Municipality reorganization (NO: "Kommunereformen")

Period Jan. 2017 — April. 2017

Role Developer Staffing 5 developers Volume 100%

Description My part of the project was to partition land data into sets of inde-

pendent data to enable parallel processing without dead-locking the database. Data dependence was defined by both logical and algorithmic constraints of the data transforms, and by database indices and constraints. The partitioning was done using graph partitioning algo-

rithms.

Tools Java, Oracle SQL, Hibernate, IntelliJ IDEA, JIRA, Confluence and

Perforce

Activity A C++/OpenCL library for sparse linear algebra

Period Aug. 2015 — Dec. 2017 Role Researcher and developer

Staffing 1 researcher Volume 100%

Description Developed as part of my masters degree at the University of Oslo.

The library implements several different sparse matrix schemes and matrix-vector operations. Matrix-vector algorithms are implemented both serially, and parallel for GPUs using the OpenCL framework.

Tools C++, OpenCL, Python, CMake, and Git

Activity Prototype an Android app for logging mobile network parameters

Period June 2013 — Aug. 2014

Role Developer Staffing 1 developer

Volume June/july 2013 and 2014: 100%. Otherwise: 20%

Description The project was to determine if an Android device coupled with pro-

prietary data from the network operator could access enough parameters from the mobile network as to be usefull for logging network state and diagnosing network problems. To access enough parameters hidden Android APIs was accessed through reflection in addition to the public APIs available through the Android SDK. As the app used proprietary network data it was never meant for public use and is not

available.

Tools Android, Java, IntelliJ IDEA, Gradle, and Git